[Fate Chooses You]
[Episode 32]
No peeking at things we shouldn't see.
There are still people outside.
I know.
I'm actually fine now.
Then you
may go back and rest early.
Okay.
Well, then,
see you tomorrow morning.
See you tomorrow morning.
Junior,
rest early.
Who is your junior?
[Tianyuan Sect]
Senior Brother Bai,
I'm coming.
I bought this down the mountain.
Senior Brother Bai,
it's just for you to try.
Thank you.
The Sect Leader said
we have distinguished guests today.
He took the seniors
to Guiyuan Hall in the front.
Senior Brother Bai,
you are injured.
The Sect Leader must not have wanted
to disturb you,
so he didn't tell you.
I know.
Senior Bai! Senior Bai!
Senior Bai,
have you been recovering well recently?
Thank you for your concern.
I'm almost fully recovered.
You still need to be careful.
With vital energy damaged,
your body needs time to recover slowly.
Don't rush it.
Yes, I know.
Senior Bai,
are you busy lately?
Not really.
The Sect Leader has guests today,
and the Outer Courtyard is short of hands.
If you are free, Senior Bai,
would you like
to lend a hand?
If it's inconvenient,
please just forget it.
It's not inconvenient.
Really?
That's great.
Thank you for lending a hand, Senior Bai.
Farewell.
Wait!
What do you mean?
Fetching water?
Senior Brother Bai is
the Sect Leader's leading disciple.
How can he do such chores?
Junior Han,
this is not what I can control.
I only know that everyone who comes here
has to do this job.
Senior Bai, if you're unwilling to do it,
you can go find Manager Yu
and complain.
You...
Senior Brother Bai,
I'm so tired.
Let's rest a bit
before going up the mountain.
Alright.
Come on.
Actually, you didn't have to come.
You are from Suxin Hall, right?
You can take care of herbs
and don't need to fetch water.
At Suxin Hall,
I just do some odd jobs.
They never let me get involved
in those weighty matters.
I sneaked out,
and no one noticed.
I'd rather follow you, Senior,
and fetch water here.
When did you join the Sect?
I'm from Quan County, Luzhou.
My father is a businessman.
When my family found out
I had immortal perception,
they sold 2 shops
and pulled every string they could
to send me to Tianyuan Sect.
Come to think of it,
it's been over 10 years.
Even though it's been more than 10 years,
my skills haven't improved.
My cultivation hasn't progressed either.
Actually,
it's not too late for you to go back.
That would be so embarrassing!
They all think I'm living a dream life
at Tianyuan Sect.
If I go back now
looking this pathetic,
they'll definitely say that
it would've been better
if I didn't have immortal perception
in the first place.
By the way, Senior Brother Bai,
do you know why our sect
has to carry water every day?
I don't know.
Ordinary disciples entering the Sect
have to carry water for 3 years first.
You're a Heavenly Talent disciple,
so you definitely
haven't experienced this.
I heard that this mountain of ours
used to be a blessed place
specifically picked
by the sect founder.
But decades ago,
after the Battle of Pinghu,
for some unknown reason,
the mountain ridges and streams
quickly withered,
and the vegetation dried up,
leaving no vitality.
Yet the foot
of the mountain wasn't much affected.
The Sect Leader at the time said
this was the blessed land
handpicked by the founder.
We couldn't abandon it.
So since then,
newly entered disciples
all have to carry water up the mountain.
Who is that person?
Him?
You don't know him?
The Sect's Senior Brother Bai Zongying.
Bai Zongying?
Yeah.
Isn't he a Heavenly Talent disciple,
a Nascent Soul cultivator?
Things have changed.
Look at us.
We only need to carry water
for a couple of years.
But look at him.
Who knows how many more years
he'll have to carry it in the future?
What are you saying?
Let's go, let's go.
Senior Brother Bai,
they're talking nonsense.
Don't mind them.
Senior Brother Bai,
I heard that in the mortal world
in the past,
there was something
called the Wooden Ox and Gliding Horse.
It was made by ordinary human artisans
through craftsmanship.
With that thing to deliver goods,
even crossing mountains
was like walking on flat ground.
Unfortunately, it's lost now.
If we had that thing,
how much effort could we save?
Why are you
mixed up with demonic cultivators?
Your sect ordered you to hunt down
people from the Wushuang Society,
and you just blindly obeyed.
Have you ever read that text?
Have you ever spoken
to the demonic cultivators
you just called?
Do you know why they wanted
to copy those books?
Someone like you
will never understand
what they truly want.
[Sihe Library]
Will you play or not?
I lost again.
Come on.
I can't control anything.
I'm not playing.
Don't be such a sore loser.
I only have this much money.
I wouldn't even
buy myself a new pair of boots,
and I lost it all to you two.
Come on.
Let me see what cards you have.
You never blocked.
Don't look.
You play badly and even blame me.
Wait,
doesn't she usually
listen to you the most?
Why does she show
no mercy to you at the card table?
Sheng usually listens to me,
but she doesn't go easy on anyone
at the card table.
What's wrong?
Let me play.
You can play?
I've watched for a while
and pretty much know how to play.
Okay.
Pay up, pay up.
Give me the money. Come on.
I'm not playing.
Pay first, come on.
Don't stop playing. Let's keep going.
I haven't had enough fun yet.
My cards are just that good.
Can't help it.
You two
just took the hits and didn't fight back.
You two should've
tried to block us.
What? Are you addicted to losing?
If I were you,
I absolutely couldn't stand this.
Settle card table grudges
at the card table.
Let's keep playing.
Come on.
I'm tired.
I need to rest.
You're leaving?
Really leaving?
If you leave,
you can't win your money back!
Having lost so much,
can you two fall asleep tonight?
Stop it.
Senior Bai,
I'm very sorry,
but I have no choice.
Look,
if you live here,
you have to travel between the outer
and inner courtyards every day.
It's far and exhausting.
You don't need to cultivate now anyway.
This courtyard
can't be used for the time being.
How lonely it is living here solitarily.
Why don't you eat and live
with the outer courtyard disciples?
It's more lively.
Senior Bai,
I'm just following orders.
You should understand.
Then I won't disturb you.
I'll take my leave.
[Baosu Courtyard]
A bunch of snobs,
bastards,
and ingrates!
When the Sect Leader finds out about this,
you'll be done for!
Senior Brother Bai,
it's just ahead...
I've always been looking forward
to living with you.
Actually, I think
my poor cultivation
isn't a matter of talent at all,
but because no one has taught me properly.
This is great now.
From now on, I can just ask you directly
if there's anything I don't understand.
This is our room.
Once we settle down,
I'll show you around, Senior Brother Bai.
Actually, living here
has a lot of benefits.
I will tell you all about them
in detail later, Senior Brother Bai.
Let's go inside first.
Senior Brother Bai,
here we are.
Senior Bai?
Why is he here?
Yeah.
Senior Brother Bai, this way.
Senior Brother,
I'll sleep here,
and you can sleep next to me.
I wonder why he's here.
What happened to him?
Here you are,
freshly made buns.
They smell super meaty.
Your senior sister made them
especially for you.
When I was young and wandering outside,
I envied people with families the most.
I really lucked out
meeting your senior sister.
I heard
you also had a miserable childhood,
lacked family ties,
and suffered a lot.
Before,
you only had your master
and your senior sister as family.
In the future,
you will have three.
Give it a try.
It's delicious.
Maltose for sale!
There are kites!
Sweet and tasty, for all ages!
Why are we shopping today?
What do you want to buy?
Today is a rare good day.
Rising step by step!
Buns!
Hot buns!
Freshly steamed big buns!
Excuse me.
How much for the buns?
Eight wen each.
Sir and madam, look,
freshly steamed big buns.
I'll get you one.
Sorry.
We don't want it now.
Let's go.
We're not eating this.
Young lady,
you're reluctant to even spend 8 wen?
Why didn't you buy it?
I didn't eat much today.
I'm not full.
We'll have something better later.
Look, there's a tailor shop.
Can you go take a look with me?
Come with me to take a look.
This one looks good.
Do you like it?
I have clothes to wear.
No need to make new ones.
Hello, sir and madam.
When it comes to tailoring,
our little shop is the best
in the whole city.
Then, sir,
we'll try this one on.
Okay.
Just try it on.
It looks really good.
Full of nobility,
handsome and reserved,
you look exactly like a refined
and elegant gentleman.
If you could smile a bit,
it would look even better.
You don't like it?
I like it.
If I could eat something delicious,
I'd like it even more.
Vegetables here!
Come and take a look!
Thank you, sir.
Fresh vegetables!
Take a look!
Let's go have some mutton soup!
The sheep blood tofu stew here
is very authentic.
Let's look around a bit more.
There's a shoe and hat shop
up ahead that we haven't visited yet.
Let's go take a look.
It won't take long.
It won't take long?
Just a little while.
Let's go.
Sir,
a bowl of mutton soup, please.
Coming right up!
How about this pair? Try them on.
Xin Mei,
I am
at the Foundation Establishment Stage now,
with my stamina not as good as before.
I know.
Let's eat.
Are you hungry?
I'm almost starving to death!
Aren't you hungry?
Alright, then, let's go have dinner.
Let's go.
For real?
[Tianxiang Restaurant]
This is made of calfskin.
It sounds crisp.
You can try it.
This is made of old cowhide.
Are you sure
this is a place to eat?
Yes.
This one, this one!
Let's go.
This one is cheap.
-Happy birthday!
-Happy birthday.
♪ Caught in fate's design,
I search my soul ♪
Sir, wish you
all the best!
Wish you peace all year round
♪ What should I do to avoid
living my life in vain? ♪
and good fortune as always!
Wish you great wealth
and robust health!
♪ My blade stays clean,
untouched by dust ♪
Wish you smooth sailing in everything.
♪ Yet it's sparked thousands of wars ♪
Wish you wealth and fortune.
♪ A towering tree worn down into
a blade devoid of feeling ♪
Wish you longevity.
Wish you joyful years ahead.
♪ The heart hides its root
at the bottom of the abyss ♪
-Happy birthday.
♪ In red, I look at you
with a glimpse of shame ♪
♪ Being haunted by the spell,
even if it's cruel ♪
Time to eat.
♪ It's better than being trapped by fate ♪
♪ Between gain and loss ♪
♪ Lies a thousand years of grace ♪
♪ Even if it's soul-eroding,
collarbone-binding pain, I accept it all ♪
Didn't you say before that,
after finishing the fate
♪ Embracing pain as home,
reborn like a phoenix ♪
of Curse of Five Deficiencies,
you could have the finest wine
♪ Just to trade the rest of my days
for one true life as a human ♪
and the most delicious food
in the biggest restaurant in the capital?
It's not
completely over yet,
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
and we're not in the capital,
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
but today is your birthday.
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
So I prepared this on my own.
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
Wish you flourish like flowers and leaves,
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
enjoying the gentle spring wind
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
every year,
always smiling in the spring breeze;
and wish you longevity.
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
Thank you.
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
♪ Don't live in vain,
have a pleasant journey of life ♪
Senior Brother Bai, are you okay?
Yuanfeng,
what's wrong with you?
Are you blind?
What?
What's going on?
Isn't it Senior Bai?
Why are you sweeping here?
Senior Brother Bai, let's go.
Senior Bai.
Since returning to the mountain last time,
I haven't had a chance to see you.
How is your recovery?
Not bad.
That's good.
You may not know that
the sword-controlling technique
you are practicing now
was what our Senior Brother Bai
mastered immediately
after hearing the Sect Master
recite the incantation.
Your comprehension
is far worse
than Senior Brother Bai's.
Since we happened to meet him today,
why don't you hurry
and ask Senior Brother Bai
for advice humbly?
If you miss it today,
you might regret it.
I was just thinking
that the elegant posture
when Senior Brother Bai dodged
my flying sword just now
is as good as before.
Seems like he had expected it.
My skills are not good enough.
Hope Senior Brother Bai
can give me some guidance.
Look, guys.
Senior Brother Bai's eyes
contain infinite sword will.
They seem to exude
a chilling killing intent
that can hurt people invisibly.
It makes one feel
a chill down the spine just looking at it.
Senior Bai,
are you ignoring me?
You used to be busy with cultivation,
so we didn't dare to bother you.
But what are you busy with now?
Is sweeping the floor
really that urgent?
Shut your mouth!
Listen,
this is none of your business.
Get lost.
You want some guidance, right?
Yes,
I hope you can enlighten me,
Senior Brother Bai.
Okay.
Yuanqi,
would you dare to spar with him for a bit?
Why wouldn't I?
He's at the 5th level
of Qi Refining stage,
while you're at the 3rd level.
Even though he has started
practicing the sword-controlling technique
and you haven't,
in terms of spiritual power and skills,
there's actually
no huge gap between you two.
Don't be nervous.
He's more afraid of losing than you are.
Remember,
in a fight,
once you create distance,
you'll stand no chance of winning.
Only in close combat
can you have a chance.
Which sword technique have you
practiced the best?
Does the starting technique count?
Yes.
Use the starting technique to beat him.
Yuanqi,
what ultimate move on earth
did Senior Bai teach you?
Show me
and broaden my horizons.
Only in close combat
can you have a chance.
Don't try to defeat the rival quickly.
Just disrupt his footwork,
so he can't focus
on controlling his sword.
Once you feel his qi to control the sword,
that means you're going to win.
Yuanqi!
Come on.
Yuanqi.
Senior.
Sima Randeng!
I was just teaching him some rules.
Yuanfeng is his senior.
Disrespecting a senior
deserves a beating.
Senior Bai is also your senior.
Being so disrespectful
and arrogant and talking improperly
in front of him,
do you deserve a beating, too?
Senior Jiang,
you are from Lingji Mountain.
Why are you staying
at our Tianyuan Sect every day?
I want to be here.
It's none of your business.
Why don't you
teach me a lesson, too?
You...
You got me wrong, Senior Jiang.
I'm just worried
that there are many sect affairs
in Lingji Mountain
waiting for you to handle.
It's not your place
to drive me away.
Alright.
That's it for today.
Let's go back.
Yes.
Come on.
I haven't seen you these past few days.
I thought you had already gone back.
The past few days,
I went to Tianyin Mountain
and asked Grand Master Lingxu
for some medicine.
Then I went to Taishan Cave, too.
This is the 100-Rotation Pill
from Tianyin Mountain.
It can restore your meridians.
This is the Bone-Purifying Pill,
which can strengthen your physique.
This is Jade-Dew Nourishing Ginseng
from Taishan Cave.
They won't help.
You haven't even tried them yet.
How can you say they won't help?
You know it.
They won't work.
You should go back.
Go back to where?
Back to your sect,
Lingji Mountain.
What about you?
Me?
Where else can I go?
Of course, I'll stay here.
Stay here for what?
Wait to be bullied by others?
It's fine if you want me to leave.
But you have to come with me.
Go with you?
Yes.
If you are willing to,
we can go back
to Lingji Mountain together.
If not,
the world is so big,
and we can go anywhere.
Senior Bai,
after all these years,
you know very well
what's in my mind.
Given the way you are right now,
how could I possibly
leave you behind?
♪ Honor and disgrace;
rumors and prejudice ♪
We can never be
in a relationship.
♪ Everyone has their own take ♪
Why?
♪ Fingers coated in blood
and disasters brought about ♪
I don't care
if you are a cultivator or not.
But I care.
♪ Were never what I wanted ♪
Even if I still had
my immortal perception,
♪ The great way is fading away,
besieged by mysterious traps ♪
we still wouldn't be together.
Because I don't like you.
♪ Who dares to treat life and death
as nothing? ♪
I don't believe it.
♪ In the blink of an eye, the body
collapses, and the soul is destroyed ♪
You are saying this on purpose.
You just want to drive me away.
♪ The fire starts raging across the land ♪
♪ What do you think is ♪
♪ The most impressive farewell
in the world? ♪
It's unnecessary for me
to lie about such things.
♪ The endless slaughter and massacres ♪
I think there's
a woman
I love in my heart.
♪ Do not wait until that thin snow
on the eaves ♪
But it's not you.
♪ Turns a young man's hair white
before you regret it ♪
I can't respond
♪ When do you think ♪
to your deep feelings.
♪ The bloody strife will come to an end? ♪
♪ Burn myself to prove it
without looking back ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ Holding the morning glow in hand,
I paint the world ♪
♪ The dawn light
illuminates the vast sky ♪
♪ What do you think is ♪
♪ The most impressive farewell
in the world? ♪
♪ The endless slaughter and massacres ♪
♪ Do not wait until that thin snow
on the eaves ♪
♪ Turns a young man's hair white
before you regret it ♪
♪ When do you think ♪
♪ The bloody strife will come to an end? ♪
♪ End these everlasting battles ♪
♪ Holding the morning glow in hand,
I paint the world ♪
♪ Someone's got to clean up this mess ♪
Thank you.
Everything's here.
Come on.
I don't want to stay with him,
nor do I want to travel with him.
What...
Sheng.
The "Unparalleled Secret Magic" is
of great importance.
I'm afraid we'll encounter danger
on the way.
Didn't we agree
to split into two groups?
Even if something happens to one group,
the other can arrive safely.
Then why
can't we be in one group,
and let him go with Lu Qianqiao?
Qianqiao's cultivation realm has dropped
to the Foundation Establishment Stage.
And Lord of Rust-Sword
isn't a cultivator.
If immortal sects come to stop them,
they'll definitely be in grave danger.
What do you mean?
Are you doubting my capabilities?
Then why can't Zuo Yingying
go with them?
Why does it have to be me?
I'm not going to the Central Plains.
It has nothing to do with me.
My dear Sheng,
there's really
no other way this time.
Sorry to put you through this.
Can you do it?
Why hasn't Lu come out yet?
[Tomb of Duan Xianyin, my dear master]
Done?
Done.
Come on.
Let's go!
Even a 1,000-mile journey
with friends ends in farewell.
Let's part ways here.
You keep saying you're leaving.
So where are you going?
Going back to my hometown.
Didn't you say you grew up
in the Qinghong Sect?
You know where your hometown is?
Yes, I know.
He told me.
There are two routes back to the capital.
The western one goes through Xutuo City
and is shorter.
The eastern one goes through the desert,
but it's sparsely populated
and inconspicuous,
so it's relatively safe.
Remember to write when you get home.
Just send it to Safe Haven Inn.
We will receive it.
Got it.
Take care.
Take care on your journey.
Xutuo City is right ahead.
Past that,
there will be no suitable
places to rest and stay.
Let's go to the city
and stock up on food and water.
Alright.
You're always so thoughtful.
[Tianyuan Sect]
Mo Guan's injuries have mostly healed.
In about 10 days,
he will be fully recovered.
Senior, please have some tea.
How are things going in North Xiang?
We have sent out quite a few scouts.
Once they come out of the Liubo Temple,
they will get messages sent back.
Sect Leader,
there's a confidential letter.
[Lu Qianqiao and the others have left
North Xiang in 2 groups for the capital.]
[Lu Qianqiao and Xin Mei went west.]
They're coming back.
[Xutuo City]
[Caiyuan Inn]
Do you think
the immortal sect in the Central Plains
that Qinghong Sect colluded with
could be Zigai Mountain?
Why?
They are short of money.
But it doesn't seem like them.
They probably wouldn't dare to offend
Lingji Mountain and Tianyuan Sect
at the same time.
What if it's Tianyuan Sect?